A Guide to the William Faulkner Collection, 1957-1961
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
William Faulkner Collection 1957-1961
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6271-bf
This collection consists of 16 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the Library's microfilms of the William Faulkner manuscripts in its custody; the microfilm may be consulted by any interested party, and it will be lent through the interlibrary loan system. Materials are constantly added. Long-term loans may be arranged. Use of the microfilm will be restricted to the premises of the borrowing library. No loans will be made to individuals. Researchers should enquire of the Manuscripts Division concerning availability of microfilm of manuscripts that are pertinent to their work. Most of the literary manuscripts in our collections written by Faulkner, both holograph and typescript, have also been published in facsimile in William Faulkner Manuscripts, 25 vols (New York: Garland, 1986-87).
By the terms of the agreement by which the William Faulkner Foundation transferred the original manuscripts to the University, access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. But even these researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with the Curator of Manuscripts prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
No microfilm, electrostatic, or other types of copies may be made of materials written by William Faulkner that are in our William Faulkner Collections. Other materials in the collections may be copied subject to the normal rules of the Library established under the conditions of the Copyright Act. All copying is performed by the Printing Services Department of the University.
Acquisition Information
This material was a gift from Carl Peterson of Waukegan, Illinois on September 3, 1981.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of 16 items; 1957-1961, electrostatic copies of letters to Carl Peterson, Waukegan, Illinois, from Linton R. Massey, Kinloch, Keswick, Virginia. The corresponding letters to Massey from Peterson are located in accession #6271-ai.
Contents List
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1957 Feb 19, TLS, 1 p.
  [Regarding their personal William Faulkner Collection.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1957 Mar 1, TLS, 1 p.
  [Returning an autograph copy of his article on Sanctuary, and giving advice on collecting William Faulkner first editions.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1958 Apr 19, TLS, 1 p.
  [Thanking him for reviews and referring to William Faulkner foreign editions.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1958 May 8, TLS, 1 p.
  [Sending a complimentary copy of Seven Years Harvest and indicating difficulty of compiling a checklist of foreign editions.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1959 Jul 24, TLS, 1 p.
  [Regarding William Faulkner transferring his material from Princeton University to Alderman Library of the University of Virginia, and the upcoming exhibit to celebrate the transfer and publication of The Mansion.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1959 Jul 24, TLS, 1 p.
  [Regarding Peterson's possible participation in the exhibit.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1959 Oct 7, TLS, 1 p.
  [Regarding opening of exhibit on previous day.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1959 Nov 11, TLS, 1 p.
  [Regarding trading duplicate William Faulkner materials and expressing pleasure at their having met.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1959 Nov 24, TLS, 1 p.
  [Regarding publishing a catalogue of the exhibit.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1960 Feb 3, TLS, 2 p.
  [Regarding Peterson's project in regard to William Faulkner show at Northwestern, and on returning loaned material for exhibit.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1960 Feb 25, TLS, 1 p.
  [Mentioning a William Faulkner reading from The Mansion before the English Club.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1960 Mar 4, TLS, 1 p.
  [Regarding returned loan material and requested photostats and William Faulkner's return to Oxford, with autograph postscript on verso.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1960 Mar 19, TLS, 2 p.
  [Sending the New Republic photostat.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1960 Sep 6, TLS, 1 p.
  [Thanking him for newsletter concerning Peterson's show.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson 1960 Sep 12, TLS, 1 p.
  [Regarding William Faulkner's fall schedule and the Faulkner Exhibition catalogue.]
- Linton R. Massey to Carl Peterson, 1961 Mar 18, TNS, 1 p.
  [Regarding the William Faulkner Foundation press release.]